<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Malek Zaag</title>
    <link>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Malek Zaag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Securinets Friendly CTF 2K22 forensics writeup</title>
      <link>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/blog/securinets-friendly-ctf-2k22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/blog/securinets-friendly-ctf-2k22/</guid>
      <description>This is my first CTF writeup for two forensics tasks in the Securinets Friendly CTF which was held online from the 30th of September 2022 to the 4th of October, how you like it .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/blog/apache-kafka-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/blog/apache-kafka-demo/</guid>
      <description>Apache Kafka Introduction In this article, we are going to talk about apache kafka which is an open-source distributed streaming platform that was developed by the Apache Software Foundation. It is designed to handle large volumes of real-time data and enables the efficient processing, storage, and analysis of data streams.
kafka Cluster cluster : Our cluster can be illustrated as below :
Producer : In Kafka, a producer is a client application that is responsible for publishing data to one or more Kafka topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python implementation for the Gnutella Protocol</title>
      <link>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/projects/gnutella-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malek-zaag.netlify.app/projects/gnutella-project/</guid>
      <description>Gnutella Project Overview : This project was issued to me during my academic studies. It consists of creating a simple application that uses the peer-to-peer protocol Gnutella.
Gnutella : The Gnutella protocol is a peer-to-peer (P2P) file-sharing protocol that allows users to share files directly with each other over the Internet without the need for a central server. It was developed in 2000 and is based on a decentralized network architecture that enables users to search for and download files from other users&amp;rsquo; computers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
